Guide to the Difference, Power, and Discrimination Program Records 1970-2011
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections and Archives Research Center
- Oral History Interviews, 1998; Series 7
  - Sound Recordings
    - Sheila Ford
      - Lucille Hoard and Deborah Smith (Box-item 6.07)
      - Rhonda Prichard (Box-item 6.08)
      - Billy Hopkins and Patria Vega (Box-item 6.09)
      - Timothy Lang, November 18th (Box-item 6.10)
      - Katie Davis and Christian Bushong, November 18th and December 1st (Box-item 6.11)
    - Suzanne Gaulocher
      - Amy Chase (Box-item 6.12)
      - Jason Allen, October 26th (Box-item 6.13)
      - Johnny Tran, November 4th (Box-item 6.14)
      - Erica Raihala (Box-item 6.15)
      - Gretchen Emmert (Box-item 6.16)
      - Mandie Bewley (Box-item 6.17)
      - Heather Graham (Box-item 6.18)
      - Ondra Watson (Box-item 6.19)
      - Terri Trosper (Box-item 6.20)
      - Jason Allen, December 2nd (Box-item 6.21)
      - Johnny Trann, December 2nd (Box-item 6.22)
    - Van Thammaphourong
      - Prescilla (Box-item 6.23)
        Includes interview with an individual for whom there is no release.
      - Luc Le and Tin Tu (Box-item 6.24)
      - Mohammed and Mona (Box-item 6.25)
      - Peter and Kory (Box-item 6.26)
      - Chankrasna Tran and Go (Box-item 6.27)
  - Releases, Transcripts, and Notes
    - Armelle Denis
      - Mary McClure (Box-folder-item 3.11.01)
      - Sarin Spehar, October 18th (Box-folder-item 3.11.02)
      - Jennifer Shukri (Box-folder-item 3.11.03)
      - Patricia Sweat (Box-folder-item 3.11.04)
      - Greg Less (Box-folder-item 3.11.05)
      - Wendy Cronin (Box-folder-item 3.11.06)
      - Jeanna Bush, November 13th (Box-folder-item 3.11.07)
      - Monica Rojas, November 15th (Box-folder-item 3.11.08)
      - Sarin Spehar, November 17th (Box-folder-item 3.11.09)
      - Brian Wenzl (Box-folder-item 3.11.10)
      - Monica Rojas, November 22nd (Box-folder-item 3.11.11)
      - Nathan Bader (Box-folder-item 3.11.12)
      - Jeanna Bush, November 25th (Box-folder-item 3.11.13)
    - Becca Zimmer-Wolf
      - Cathleen Moscibrocki (Box-folder-item 3.12.01)
      - Mandie Bewley (Box-folder-item 3.12.02)
      - Silas Richardson (Box-folder-item 3.12.03)
      - Andrew Biskey (Box-folder-item 3.12.04)
      - Jamie Denton (Box-folder-item 3.12.05)
      - Jay Kerby (Box-folder-item 3.12.06)
      - Danny Saecho (Box-folder-item 3.12.07)
      - John Steele (Box-folder-item 3.12.08)
      - Jeff Campbell (Box-folder-item 3.12.09)
    - David Baldassano
      - Susan Nall (Box-folder-item 3.13.01)
      - Derek Ottele (Box-folder-item 3.13.02)
      - James Rogers (Box-folder-item 3.13.03)
      - Faron Anslow (Box-folder-item 3.13.04)
      - Jesse Putman (Box-folder-item 3.13.05)
      - Angela Lau (Box-folder-item 3.13.06)
      - James Udoka (Box-folder-item 3.13.07)
      - Colleen Cordis (Box-folder-item 3.13.08)
      - Maija Gunderson (Box-folder-item 3.13.09)
      - Megan Kalstad (Box-folder-item 3.13.10)
    - Eben Haase
      - Daniel Olvera (Box-folder-item 3.14.01)
      - Brittney Powell (Box-folder-item 3.14.02)
      - Jesse Downing (Box-folder-item 3.14.03)
      - Jose Pizano (Box-folder-item 3.14.04)
      - Renato Quintero (Box-folder-item 3.14.05)
      - Jenny Semadeni (Box-folder-item 3.14.06)
      - T. J. Jeppesen (Box-folder-item 3.14.07)
      - Marisa Fernandez (Box-folder-item 3.14.08)
      - Ramona Flores (Box-folder-item 3.14.09)
      - Maria Villalobos (Box-folder-item 3.14.10)
    - Heather Burns
      - Lisa N. (Box-folder-item 3.15.01)
      - Nancy (Box-folder-item 3.15.02)
      - Angela Cordova (Box-folder-item 3.15.03)
      - Michael Sugihara (Box-folder-item 3.15.04)
      - William Andersen (Box-folder-item 3.15.05)
      - Benn Eilers (Box-folder-item 3.15.06)
      - Dan Auger (Box-folder-item 3.15.07)
      - Tammi Jackman (Box-folder-item 3.15.08)
      - David Jackman (Box-folder-item 3.15.09)
      - Kristina Small (Box-folder-item 3.15.10)
    - Jennifer Leaver
      - Andrew Moen (Box-folder-item 3.16.01)
      - Machelle Nelson (Box-folder-item 3.16.02)
      - Fredrik Kummernes (Box-folder-item 3.16.03)
      - Dorothy Sandoval (Box-folder-item 3.16.04)
      - Laura Baxter (Box-folder-item 3.16.05)
      - Jaime Race (Box-folder-item 3.16.06)
      - Kom-Dui So (Box-folder-item 3.16.07)
        Also known as Anthony
      - Jeremy Baker (Box-folder-item 3.16.08)
      - Ellie Larsen (Box-folder-item 3.16.09)
      - Charlie Bisgord (Box-folder-item 3.16.10)
    - Laura Henderson
      - Michael Edwards (Box-folder-item 3.17.01)
      - Ravi Puri (Box-folder-item 3.17.02)
      - Lisa Hobart (Box-folder-item 3.17.03)
      - Karianne Stinson (Box-folder-item 3.17.04)
      - Justin Timmons (Box-folder-item 3.17.05)
      - Melanie Spraggins (Box-folder-item 3.17.06)
      - Suzanne Gaulocher (Box-folder-item 3.17.07)
      - Jessica Leahy (Box-folder-item 3.17.08)
      - Timothy Tedder (Box-folder-item 3.17.09)
      - Kevin Pardew (Box-folder-item 3.17.10)
      - Jill Brunell (Box-folder-item 3.17.11)
      - Brenda Johnson (Box-folder-item 3.17.12)
    - Nicko Widjaja
      - Thomas Tu (Box-folder-item 3.18.01)
      - Ceryl Susilo and Mutiara Moesaffa (Box-folder-item 3.18.02)
      - Jamie Toman and Khaled Abmusallam (Box-folder-item 3.18.03)
      - Sutrisno Amidjojo (Box-folder-item 3.18.04)
      - Patrick (Box-folder-item 3.18.05)
      - Frans Marbun (Box-folder-item 3.18.06)
      - Andrew Kim (Box-folder-item 3.18.07)
      - Contextual Notes (Box-folder-item 3.18.08)
    - Pei-Yao Lee
      - Chi-Yu Wang (Box-folder-item 3.19.01)
      - Carl Erhardt (Box-folder-item 3.19.02)
      - Michael Giles (Box-folder-item 3.19.03)
      - Gregory Jones (Box-folder-item 3.19.04)
      - Emily Schlumbohm (Box-folder-item 3.19.05)
      - Takayuki Nishio (Box-folder-item 3.19.06)
      - I-Ping Huang (Box-folder-item 3.19.07)
      - Doug Holdt (Box-folder-item 3.19.08)
      - Terry Wright (Box-folder-item 3.19.09)
      - Minori Fukushima (Box-folder-item 3.19.10)
    - Sheila Ford
      - Rhonda Prichard (Box-folder-item 3.20.01)
      - Timothy Lang, October 20th (Box-folder-item 3.20.02)
      - Christian Bushong, October 29th (Box-folder-item 3.20.03)
      - Billy Hopkins (Box-folder-item 3.20.04)
      - Patria Vega (Box-folder-item 3.20.05)
      - Mary Martin (Box-folder-item 3.20.06)
      - Terry Wright (Box-folder-item 3.20.07)
      - Lucille Hoard (Box-folder-item 3.20.08)
      - Deborah Smith (Box-folder-item 3.20.09)
      - Timothy Lang, November 18th (Box-folder-item 3.20.10)
      - Katie Davis (Box-folder-item 3.20.11)
      - Christian Bushong, December 1st (Box-folder-item 3.20.12)
      - Interview Journals 1-12 (Box-folder-item 3.20.13)
    - Suzanne Gaulocher
      - Amy Chase (Box-folder-item 3.21.01)
      - Jason Allen, October 26th (Box-folder-item 3.21.02)
      - Johnny Tran, November 4th (Box-folder-item 3.21.03)
      - Erica Raihala (Box-folder-item 3.21.04)
      - Gretchen Emmert (Box-folder-item 3.21.05)
      - Mandie Bewley (Box-folder-item 3.21.06)
      - Heather Graham (Box-folder-item 3.21.07)
      - Ondra Watson (Box-folder-item 3.21.08)
      - Terri Trosper (Box-folder-item 3.21.09)
      - Jason Allen, December 2nd (Box-folder-item 3.21.10)
      - Johnny Tran, December 2nd (Box-folder-item 3.21.11)
    - Van Thammaphourong
      - Prescilla (Box-folder-item 3.22.01)
      - Luc Le and Tin Tu (Box-folder-item 3.22.02)
      - Mohammed (Box-folder-item 3.22.03)
      - Peter (Box-folder-item 3.22.04)
      - Chankrasna Tran (Box-folder-item 3.22.05)
      - Kory (Box-folder-item 3.22.06)
      - Mona (Box-folder-item 3.22.07)
      - Go (Box-folder-item 3.22.08)
  - RESTRICTED: Transcripts and Notes from Interviews without Releases
    - RESTRICTED: Nicko Widjaja (Box-folder 7.01)
    - RESTRICTED: Sheila Ford (Box-folder 7.02)
    - RESTRICTED: Suzanne Gaulocher (Box-folder 7.03)
    - RESTRICTED: Van Thammaphourong (Box-folder 7.04)
- Program Administration, 1991-2005; Series 8
  Series 9 documents the administration of the program and includes enrollment data, budgets, position descriptions for the program director and staff, proposals, lists of faculty who have completed the DPD faculty seminar or teach DPD courses, and surveys and evaluations of the program. Materials documenting a 2004 celebration of the DPD Program at Oregon State are part of this series. Also of note is a 2003 presentation to the Provost's Council. This series includes born-digital materials (174 files; 3.8 Mbytes) that are available to researchers in the Reading Room.
  - Proposals/Drafts for Difference, Power, and Discrimination, 1991-2003 (Box-folder 3.23)
  - Enrollment Data, 1992-2004 (Box-folder 3.24)
  - Grant Proposals, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 3.25)
  - Lists, 1993-1998 (Box-folder 3.26)
    Faculty who have completed the DPD Seminar and/or teach DPD courses.
  - Krishna- Grants Search, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 3.27)
  - Difference, Power, and Discrimination Budget and Facts, 1994-2005 (Box-folder 3.28)
  - Internal Research Fellowships, 1995 (Box-folder 3.29)
  - OSU: Minority Fellowship Pilot Program, 1995 (Box-folder 3.30)
  - Survey/Analyses of Faculty Seminars and Juniors from DPD Courses, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 3.31)
  - Survey of Undergraduate Departments, 1998 (Box-folder 3.32)
  - Essay Contest, Minutes, and Appendices, 1998-2004 (Box-folder 3.33)
  - Evaluations/Questionnaire, 1999 (Box-folder 3.34)
  - Position Descriptions, 1999-2004 (Box-folder 3.35)
  - Presentation Scripts for Difference, Power, and Discrimination Program at OSU, 2002 (Box-folder 3.36)
  - Development Grants, 2003 (Box-folder 3.37)
  - Writing Intensive Curriculum (WIC) Grant, 2003 (Box-folder 3.38)
  - A Celebration and Honoring Ceremony, 2004 (Box-folder 3.39)
  - DPD Anthology and Chapter 10, 2004 (Box-folder 3.40)
    Difference, Power, and Discrimination
  - Program Evaluation Retreat at Kah-Nee-Ta, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 3.41)
  - Conference - Oregon Institute on Ethnic Diversity, 1994 (Box-folder 3.42)
  - Conference - Oregon Women in Higher Education, 1995 (Box-folder 3.43)
  - Oregon Assembly for Black Affairs, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 3.44)
  - Administrative Files, 1994-2003
    Materials documenting the administration of the DPD Programs including planning for special events, budgets, meeting minutes, assessments and evaluations, and correspondence. Of special note is a 2003 presentation to the Provost's Council. These born digital materials 120 files; 2.5 Mbytes) are primarily Word documents; other formats include Word Perfect, Excel, and Powerpoint files. Several images are also part of this digital folder.
  - Course Histories, 1999
    Materials documenting DPD courses. These born digital materials (39 files; 763 kbytes) are all Word documents. The materials are available for researchers in the Reading Room.
  - Faculty Essays, 1997
    Essays submitted by DPD faculty. These digital materials (4 files; 29 kbytes) are all Word documents. The materials are available for researchers in the Reading Room.
  - How To, 2002
    Instructions prepared by DPD staff to document administrative and office operations. These born-digital materials (11 files; 581 kbytes) consist of Word documents and one Microsoft Publisher file. The records are available for researchers in the Reading Room.
- Publications, 1994-2006; Series 9
  Series 10 consists of publications documenting the administration and activities of the DPD Program. It includes ReVisions, the quarterly newsletter produced by the Program, flyers, brochures, and posters. The newsletter lists DPD courses that have been approved by the Baccalaureate Core Committee, announcements of events, short articles by faculty teaching DPD courses, and provides information about the staff and administration of the Program.
  This series also includes flyers, brochures, and posters -- including a poster promoting the lecture presented by Nikki Giovanni as the OSU DPD Distinguished Lecturer and Keynote Speaker for the Conference on Gender and Culture held in April 2002.
  Born-digital materials (24 files; 2.8 Mbytes) in this series include the Fall 2000 ReVisions newsletter; manuscript files of the book about the DPD Program written by Jun Xing; and Writing for Change by Janet Lockhart and Susan M. Shaw. These materials are available for researchers in the Reading Room.
  - Flyers, Brochures, and Posters for Special Events, 1994-2005 (Box-folder 3.45)
  - ReVisions, 1994-2006 (Box-folder 3.46)
  - Poster for Nikki Giovanni lecture, 2002 (Box-folder 8.1)
  - DPD Book, 2006
    Manuscript of the book, Teaching for Change: The Difference, Power, and Discrimination Model, by Jun Xing published in 2007 by Lexington Books. These born digital materials (22 files; 1.1 Mbytes) consist solely of Word documents. These records are available for researchers in the Reading Room.
  - ReVisions Newsletter, 2000
    Fall 2000 issue of the DPD newsletter. This digital folder consists of one Microsoft Publisher file (721 kbytes) and is available for researchers in the Reading Room.
  - Writing for Change, 2002
    Writing for Change: Raising Awareness of Difference, Power, and Discrimination, 2nd Edition, by Janet Lockhart and Susan M. Shaw. This digital folder includes one PDF file (474 kbytes) that is available for researchers in the Reading Room.
- Video and Sound Recordings, 1987-2008; Series 10
  Series 10 consists of recordings of Difference, Power, and Discrimination Program Distinguished Lectures at Oregon State University by Nikki Giovanni (2002) and Gloria Anzaldua (2003); a radio program about Audre Lorde, and two ABC News 20/20 programs. The radio and ABC News programs may have been used in training and workshops offered by the DPD Program. The lectures by Giovanni and Anzaldua are available online.
  - A Radio Profile of Audre Lorde, 1987 (Box-folder 9.1)
    This radio profile first aired on WGBH radio in Boston in February 1987. This audiocassette was prepared by Profile Productions. Jennifer Abod was producer and narrator.
  - Recorded Lectures at Oregon State University, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 9.2)
    2 VHS tapes
    - Nikki Giovanni, 2002; 1 (Box-folder 9.2)
      Recorded at LaSells Stewart Center on April 18, 2002. The sound quality of the original recording is poor. This videotape has been digitized and is available online.
    - Gloria Anzaldua - 2003 Distinguished Lecturer, 2 (Box-folder 9.2)
      Recorded on April 24, 2003. Leslie Burns introduced the speaker and Jubilate, a women's choir in Corvallis, performed before the lecture -- Geography of Selves: Identity and the New Tribalism. This videotape has been digitized and is available online.
  - ABC News 20/20 programs, 2007-2008 (Box-folder 9.3)
    2 DVDs
    - Waiting on the World to Change, 2007; 1 (Box-folder 9.3)
      Broadcast on January 26, 2007.
    - They're Not Like Us - Privilege in America, 2008; 2 (Box-folder 9.3)
      Broadcast on September 10, 2008.
- Born-Digital Materials, 1997-2008; Series 11
  Series 11 consists of born-digital materials captured on April 18, 2008 as a back-up of http://oregonstate.edu/dept/dpd. The records include electronic versions of the ReVisions newsletter, administrative program files, materials pertaining to the faculty seminar, and associated documentation and correspondence. The bulk of the materials are for 2002-2008. The original arrangement of these materials is retained. File formats include *.html, Word documents, Microsoft Publisher files, PDFs, and images. These materials (217 files; 13.6 Mbytes) are available for researchers in the Reading Room.